I was always wondering...
我常常幻想
what my future would be like.
长大后的我会是怎样的
Good morning, Truly.
真心姐早
Morning.
早
Graduate from my dream school,
从理想的学校毕业
fully develop my potential,
发挥才华
realize my dreams.
实现梦想
Bravo!
BRAVO
The lucrative deal in Shenzhen
深圳的大单
is finally signed to us.
终于签约成功
Listen,
来
you should learn more from Truly.
要多多向林真心学习
Do everything you can for the company.
替公司卖命
Fight for more good deals!
争取更多的好业绩
Cheers!
Cheers
Thank you boss.
谢谢老板
Thank you.
谢谢  · · ·
Wow!
哎
What is this, Truly?
真心姐这什么
So shiny!
好闪哦
Congratulations!
恭喜姐
Double good news!
双喜临门哪
And have a perfect relationship.
然后遇到一份完美的爱情
My life will shine...
我的人生会像钻石一样
like a diamond.
闪闪发亮
Hsin, go tell her.
小欣 你去说啦
We've worked over time for so many days...
都连续加班好几天了
Truly.
真心姐
Can we go now?
我们可以下班了吗
Sure, bye bye!
可以  · · ·再见
Bye bye.
再见
- See you tomorrow. - Bye bye.
- 明天见 辛苦了啊 - 再见
Thank you, Truly!
谢谢真心姐
Hurray!
喔 太好罗
Shall we got for spicy hot pot?
我们去吃麻辣锅好不好
Sure.
好呀
Which restaurant? I'll make a reservation.
想吃哪一家 我先订
Hello?
喂
What time do you think it is?
都几点了
Why are you still in the office?
你怎么还会在公司
I've been waiting for 5 minutes.
我已经等了你五分钟了
Sorry.
对不起
I'll go to the restaurant now.
我现在立刻赶过去
If you're not here in 5 minutes, I'll leave.
五分钟不到我就走人
That's not enough time!
五分钟怎么来得及
It'll take me half an hour to get there.
我过去餐厅都要半个小时
Hello?
喂  · · ·
Shit.
死定了
Conference call with Edinburgh at midnight.
半夜爱丁堡那边要视讯会议
Your team will stay to prepare for it.
你们这一组留下来准备
But I have...
可是我晚上  · · ·
I'll do it now.
我立刻就去准备
Look at Truly.
学学你们真心姐
What a role model!
优秀
Yes, sir.
是
Everyone.
大家
Let's stay a little longer to work on it.
再留晚一点准备一下开会资料
Go! Go! Go!
加油
Earlier done, earlier home.
早点作完早点回家
No one ever told me,
从来没有人告诉我
the truth is... when you grow up,
原来长大以后
it's likely you'll have a not-so-good job,
你可能只会做一份不怎么样的工作
be in a not-so-good relationship,
谈一场不怎么样的感情
and live a not-so-good life.
将就着过一段不怎么样的生活
Dunno what he wants to eat.
不知道喜欢吃什么
It seems like Hsin is on a diet...
小欣好像在减肥
Go! Go! Go! Early done, early home.
加油！早点作完早点回家喔
She's the one who told us to stay.
就是她叫我们加班的啊
I won't get her bonus anyway.
业绩奖金也没有我的份
The manager told us to learn from Truly.
早上有没有听到经理说要跟真心一样
Fuck! Who wants to learn from her?
靠夭！谁要跟她一样啊
Working overtime for little salary.
工作超时 薪水又不够用
She treats the company as her family.
她把公司当家人
The company treats her as animal.
公司把她当畜牲
To be honest,
其实我觉得她这种人
I feel bad for people like her.
也是满可怜的啦
I hope I won't be like her when I get old.
希望我老了以后不会跟她一样
Who wants to be like her! Miserable.
谁要跟她一样啊 那不就很衰
I think...
我想
if I ran into this woman
十八岁的我
when I was 18,
如果在街上偶然遇到这个女人
I would have definitely laughed at her
一定也会和他们一样
like them, without mercy.
毫不留情的嘲笑她
Yabiyabi. Good evening everyone.
呀比  · · ·晚安 各位
This is Guangyu.
我是光禹
Do you like who you are now?
你喜欢现在的自己吗
When we grow up,
长大之后的我们
we become sophisticated and tend to compromise
为了生存 会变得世故
in order to survive.
容易妥协
We become someone we don't recognize.
甚至变得都不认识自己是谁
Would you sometimes miss the time when you
偶尔你是不是会怀念当时那个单纯
were rather naive and dared to dream?
勇敢作梦的自己呢
Is that part of you still there?
那个你 现在还在身体里吗
Do you still remember those people
而那些生命中很重要的人
who played an important role in your life?
你都还记得吗
(MY DREAM: GO TO ANDY LAU'S CONCERT...)
(我的梦想: 去看刘德华的演唱会...)
Tonight,
今天晚上
we'll start our program with
我们在节目一开始
this song from me to you all.
就要送给大家这首歌
A song we haven't heard for a long time.
好久没有听到的歌
"Forget Love Water" by Andy Lau.
刘德华的忘情水
Good morning. Here is the latest news...
为您播报晨间新闻
yesterday Alec Su of The Little Tigers
小虎队成员苏有朋
said he dropped out of Taiwan University.
昨日宣布从台大机械工程系大三休学
The whole entertainment world is in shock.
震惊了所有演圈  · · ·
Are you giving birth? Are you done or not?
你是在生孩子喔 是好了没啦
I'm done!
好了啦
Back then, I was turning 18
那年即将十八岁的我
and truly understood something important:
深深明白一件很重要的事
History has proven that, there are mainly
从古至今
two types of young girls in the world.
这世上的少女大概分两种
Hey, here she comes.
出来了  · · ·
Wow! How elegant.
哇塞 她好优雅哦
Oh my God! She's gorgeous!
天啊 她也太漂亮了吧
So cute!
好可爱哦
Pretty girls who are popular...
受男生欢迎的漂亮女生
Don't go!
不要走
- Wait for me! - Tao Minmin!
- 等等我 - 陶敏敏
And
和
those who are not pretty.
不漂亮的
My name is Lin Truly.
我是林真心
Sorry!
对不起
I'm the one who just fell on the street.
是现在仆街的这个
If you're a guy,
如果你男生
let me tell you a story of an ordinary girl
接下来我要告诉你
who you've never bothered to care about
你们从小到大从不想关心的平凡少女
and her ordinary life.
她的平凡人生
= Our Times =
Back then, the most important decision
那时候的我们
we had to make every day
每天最重要的抉择是
was what to eat for breakfast.
早餐要吃铁板面还是萝卜糕
Can you please hurry up?
可以快一点吗
Is it that tough to decide?
有这么难选吗
The biggest lie we had ever told
扯过最大的谎是
was on the day of exam,
今天要考试
we'd say...
但  · · ·
I didn't prepare for it.
我昨天没念耶
Neither did I.
我昨天也没念耶
I thought we were having math exam.
我以为要考数学耶
The most luxurious thing to do,
最奢侈的享受
was to go shopping in the bookstore.
是到书局Shopping
Back then,
在那个年代
that was our department store.
那就是我们的新光三越
The biggest dream we had
最大的梦想是
was to meet our idols
有一天
one day.
能和偶像碰面
The shame of being shameless is shameless.
无耻之耻无耻矣 · · ·
Somehow young girls of that time
不知道为什么
had some kind of fantasy.
那时候少女有一种错觉
We believed whoever collected most photos
好像谁买了最多照片
would be the most qualified person
长大以后
to marry him.
谁就最有资格嫁给他
This is Small.
这是小只
Although large in size,
虽然长得很大只
she is a super romantic teenage girl.
但是超有少女心
Kaneshiro Takeshi is her ex,
前男友是金城武
and now.
现在
Aaron Kwok is her fiance.
宣称是郭富城的未婚妻
Even I am not married yet,
我都还没有嫁人
how come you already have a husband?
你怎么会有老公
Boss Lau...
刘老大
However hard you try, he'll never reply.
你写给他三百三十三封他也不会回
What you do is called shameless.
你们俩个的行为简直就是无耻的代表
This is Meimei.
这是何美
Very cheerful,
生性活泼
but... almost too cheerful.
但 有点活泼过了头
Girls, where are you going?
我的好姊妹 你们要去哪里呀
Back in our teenage life, we were always
少女时代的我们每天除了念书
doing silly things apart from studying.
做的都是一些穷极无聊的蠢事
And this is the silliest
而以下这件
among all.
更是蠢事中的第一
Ouyang is coming. He's so handsome.
欧阳来了 好帅喔
Hey, be quiet. Come on.
好了 别吵了 赶快看看
He has a style. He's here.
好有型喔 他走过来了
There is always a boy like this,
每个少女的青春里
in every teenage girl's life.
都有一个这样的男孩
Thank you.
谢谢
It's on me.
我请客
- 60 please. - 60.
总共六十块
六十
Somehow they're always basketball players,
不知道为什么 他们总是篮球校队
secret crush for every girl in the school.
不知道为什么 全校女生总是一起暗恋他
I feel Ouyang is looking at me.
我觉得欧阳看过来了啦
I think he's looking at me.
我觉得他是在看我耶
We can giggle for the whole day
然后因为他的一个眼神
just because of a look from him.
傻笑一整天
Dear all, can you please stop helping
麻烦各位同学
those idiots send love letters
不要再帮那些臭男生传情书
to our Minmin?
给我们的敏敏好吗
Especially this kind of idiot,
尤其是这种
who misused "disney" for "destiny".
把"缘"写成"绿"的白痴
This kind of ordinary, simple life
这平凡简单的人生
was turned upside down by that very letter.
直到收到那封改变一切的信
(TO LIN TRULY)
(林真心 收)
This is a chain letter from South African
这是一封来自南非传教士
missionary Anthony DE Croud.
Antnony DE Croud的幸运信
Now the good luck is bestowed on you.
现在这个幸运降临到你的身上
Send 5 copies to your friends,
抄录五份给你的朋友
and the good luck is yours.
可以得到幸运
Otherwise disasters will be waiting for you.
反之 你将大难临头
In 1979, Mr. Chen from Taiwan did not
一九七九年
take the letter seriously and tore it apart.
台湾的陈先生不信此信将之撕毁
He died in a car accident the next day.
隔天他就车祸身亡
In 1963, Flayre from Holland burnt it...
一九六三年 荷兰富莱尔将此信烧毁
3 days later, his mother started to...
三天后 他的母亲罹患怪病
suffer an incurable disease.
医生束手无策
(YOU STILL HAVE THREE DAYS. GOOD LUCK.)
(你还有三天时间. 祝你好运.)
The person I want to send chain letter to
我最想把幸运信给他的人
the most, is Lin Sincere.
是林诚意
My brother.
我的哥哥
Your brother advanced
你哥哥这次考试吼
5 places in this exam.
进步了五名呐
Last time he got the lowest score. Besides,
他上次考全班最后一名
he's spent 7 years on a 5-year program...
而且他五专念了七年还没毕业
Don't you talk back!
你还顶嘴
Only if you could get half of the grade
你的分数要是有人家那个陶敏敏
of Tao Minmin's.
一半好就好
30 points.
考三十分
You even tried to alter it
还改分数
with a different color.
用不一样的颜色
How stupid!
怎么那么笨呐
My red pen ran out of ink.
啊就红笔没有水啊
Couldn't you borrow one from your teacher?
啊不会去跟老师借哦
That's right.
对啊
Take it.
来啦
Thank you mom.
嗯 谢谢妈
Take one more.
多吃一只
Thank you dad!
谢谢爸
Many of you probably had the same thought,
应该很多人都样想过
"Am I'm really my parents' child?"
从小我就怀疑自己不是爸妈亲生的
But if my brother's family is really ruined,
但考虑到万一家破人亡
I might suffer as well.
可能会连累到我
So I dismissed that idea.
就打消了念头
Therefore...
所以
I gave the first letter
第一封信
to him.
我给了他
Lin Truly.
林真心
Question 1:
第一题
If the balls are put in the order of red,
红蓝绿三种颜色的球依序排列
blue, green, what's the color of ball 555?
第五百五十五颗是什么颜色
It's ok if you don't know the answer,
答不出来就算了
but why drawing it like this?
你画这么认真你是在写生吗
Don't you dodge!
还躲
There must be a psycho teacher like this
每个人的学生时代
in everyone's school years.
一定都有这样变态的老师
"Wang Baidan".
"王白丹"
Our home room teacher and math teacher.
我们班导兼数学老师
We all call him.
大家都叫他
"Wang Badan" (ASSHOLE)
"王八蛋"
I haven't even started!
我还没打咧
Come back.
过来
You're even louder than me.
叫的比我还大声
I gave the second letter
第二封信
to Tao Minmin.
我寄给了陶敏敏
It's definitely not because I envy her
绝对不是因为羡慕她漂亮
for her beauty or popularity.
嫉妒她受欢迎
Not even because
更不是因为
she's that girl who could
她是能被那个 "他"
get his attention.
注意到的女孩
It's simply because she lives next door.
纯粹只是因为她住在我家隔壁
Right on my way home.
顺手而已喔
What? A good student?
哎哟好学生喔
Do the recycling.
做资源回收
Hey you.
同学
Kick it back.
踢过来
Ouyang Extraordinary.
欧阳非凡
I might've seen this disgusting name before.
这么假掰的名字好像在哪里看过
As there is a "God" in every school,
就像学校里一定有男神
there is also a "boss".
每间学校也一定有个老大
Stand up.
起立
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Last number of the last class in 3rd grade.
三年级最后一班最后一号
He's the boss who leads our school in
就是那个代表一高和别的学校争地盘
turf wars and charge others protection fee.
收保护费的老大
Rumor has it that
传闻
he fights, runs away from home, he's on drug
他打架 械斗 逃家 吸毒
has killed people, set fire...
杀过人 纵过火
So notorious that no school wants him,
恶名远播到整区高中联合拒收
except for First High School...
只有一高愿意收留他
How daring are you to be here.
敢来这里嚣张
You despise us the 12 Masters of First High?
瞧不起我们一高十二少
What about Ten Brothers from Chuoshui River?
林北还浊水溪十兄弟
Kill them.
乎死
He's even appointed as school patrol.
学校还以毒攻毒让他担任纠察队
Indecent clothing.
服仪不整
Eating while walking.
边走边吃
Studying too hard.
书读太多
Too matured body.
发育太好
First High...
一高
has since been trapped in the devil's clutches.
就此被困在他的魔掌之中
Recycle it!
资源回收
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 干什么
Why bully others like this?
你为什么要这样欺负别人
What the hell are you guys doing?
在干什么
Here comes the director,
主任来了
let's go.
老大 快闪
Come on! Go, go.
赶快走 快一点 · · ·
Chicken.
臭俗仔
Therefore...
所以我决定
I decided to send him the third letter.
寄出第三封信
Guile.
阿力固
G your mother.
阿你的头啦
Sorry
(TO HSU TAIYU)
It's pink
粉红色
with fragrance.
有香味
Love letter?
情书耶
Aren't you over the moon, boss?
老大爽不爽啊
Over what! Get lost.
爽你个头 闪啦
Who has the guts to write him a love letter?
哪个不怕死的居然敢写情书给他
Oh, he was even blushing.
哦 他刚还脸红
Blushing! Hahahaha.
脸红耶 哈 · · ·
He must be over the moon now.
他在心里一定超爽的
Not just over the moon...
什么爽而已
Over the whole world!
简直是爽翻天啦
老大 · · ·
Boss.
Did you hear about it already?
你们俩个有没有听说
Hsu Taiyu had a car accident yesterday.
那个徐太宇昨天出车祸了耶
Lin Truly...
林真心 · · ·
If I find out who cursed boss,
如果被我抓到是谁诅咒老大的
I'll make sure to break his arms and legs.
林北绝对乎他断手断脚
Sorry, she needs to take her medicine.
对不起 她该吃药了
Lin Truly, let's go.
林真心 走啦 · · ·
Why are you so heavy!
你怎么那么重啊
Go.
走了啦
Boss, watch your step.
老大小心
Someone is spreading the rumor,
有同学在谣传
saying this year's school anniversary
说今年的校庆
will be suspended due to track renovation.
会因为整修跑道而停办
Let me clarify it here.
我在这里郑重说明
This year, school anniversary festival
今年的校庆
will be held as scheduled.
会如期举行
Since I'm retiring from First High soon.
个人即将在一高退休了
The new director will take over
接任的训导主任
the responsibility as the organizer.
届时将会承办相关的事宜
Last but not least, do not leave yet.
最后呢 请各位同学先不要离开
School patrol is now conducting
纠察队
a surprise safety inspection.
现在正在各班实施突击安全检查
Dahe.
大贺
Breast baring.
露点
That's too nasty.
太严重啦
Make a note.
记起来
Confiscate it.
没收
Hey you.
同学
We need to talk.
有事找你
Where are we going?
我们现在要去哪里啊
Just follow us.
走就对了
No!
我不要
Enjoy, boss.
老大请享用
In 1979,
一九七九年
Mr. Chen from Taiwan...
台湾的陈先生
did not take the letter seriously
不信此信
and tore it apart.
将之撕毁
The next day he died in a car accident.
隔天就车祸身亡
So it's you.
原来是这样
Whose films do you like?
你喜欢谁的电影
蛤
What?
Who?
谁的啦
S...Stephen Chow.
周 · · ·周星驰
Which film do you like best?
你最喜欢他哪一部片
All... "All's Well, Ends Well".
家 · · ·家家家有囍事
How many "all" s?
几个家
One.
一个家
Your birthday?
生日
April 19.
四月十九
Good, you're honest.
很好 没有说谎
What don't you like about me?
你对我有什么意见
Nothing.
没有意见
I...think... you're
我 · · ·觉得 · · ·你
tall...
又高
and cute...
又帅
and if I look closely...
近看
You even look a bit like Andy Lau?
还很像刘德华耶
I know you sent the chain letter to me
我知道你为了他
because of him.
才寄幸运信给我的
No!
不可以
What no?
啥米不可以
I can't change the film?
换片不可以喔
Would you like to change the film?
客人要换片吗
Yes, to...
换
All... "All's Well, Ends Well".
家 · · ·家家有囍事吧
Sure, just a moment.
好 稍等
Let's...
我们
be friends.
交个朋友吧
What?
蛤
You just introduced yourself.
刚刚你已经自我介绍完啦
In Taiyu's dictionary, friend means
徐太宇对"朋友"的定义
unconditional devotion.
就是无条件对他付出
In order to protect Ouyang,
为了保护欧阳的安危
I'm willing to listen to Hsu Taiyu.
我只能听命于徐太宇
Be his slave.
做他的奴隶
Auntie.
老板娘
One sesame noodle.
我要一碗麻酱面
Don't put sesame dressing and noodles
麻酱跟面
together. They need to be separated.
它们不可以放在一起要分开
No fatty no lean for braised pork rice
然后卤肉饭不要肥肉也不要瘦肉
but half half.
要半肥半瘦
And veggie tofu soup without spring onion.
然后青菜豆腐汤
Two eggs in it but don't beat it.
两颗蛋 不要葱花也不要打成蛋花
Thank you.
谢谢
If no spring onion in veggie tofu soup,
青菜豆腐汤都不要加葱花
why have it on sesame noodles?
为什么麻酱面上面有葱花
Get a new one!
重买
Wait.
等一下
This is your reward.
奖励你的
Autographed photo of Andy Lau.
刘德华签名照
It's Andy Low from the TV show.
是百战百胜 "刘的华"
Here.
这边
I thought you forgot your book for math
你不是数学课要校外教学没带课本吗
excursion, where are the other people?
其他人咧
Idiot.
白痴
What kind of excursion for math class?
谁数学课校外教学啊
Hurry up.
快点
The movie starts at 2.
电影两点开始
Ah...
欵
The bell rang already, I'm going back.
已经打钟了 我要回去上课了
Then who'll get food for me?
那谁帮我买吃的
Who'll collect my trash?
谁帮我收垃圾
Who'll fan for me?
谁帮我扇风
I can't climb the wall.
我不会翻墙
So...
所以
I really can't do this.
真的不行啦
You wanna die?
你想死吗
What if the teacher finds out?
被老师发现怎么办啊
I've never skipped class in my life...
我从来没有翘过课
If you've never done that in your uniform,
没穿过高中制服翘过一次课
you'll regret in the future.
长大以后才会后悔好吗
You're so heavy.
好重
Hurry up.
快点溜
Don't goof off.
不要混
Can I go back for tutorial class?
我可不可以回去上辅导课啊
Attach yourself to the end of the line.
你等一下接在最后面
Hsu Taiyu, I had enough!
徐太宇 我不想玩了
Are you ok?
没事吧
Are you alright?
还好吗
I'm ok...
没事
Then go get squid balls for me!
那去帮我买花枝丸
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Thank you.
谢谢
Go away! What are you looking at? Sit down.
闪啦 看啥 坐好啦
Quickly!
快走
Sit!
坐下
Sit tight!
坐好啦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Don't you dare touch my gal...
林北ㄟ七辣你也敢动
干嘛
What's wrong!
Holding hands when roller skating?
溜冰还手牵手
How can you do it without holding hands?
啊溜冰是不用手牵手腻
Shut up!
还顶嘴
What?
欵
Kill him.
乎死啊
Sakuraki.
樱木
Boss.
老大
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Boss, are you ok?
老大你没事吧
It's ok.
没事啦
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
If I didn't have final exam this afternoon,
要不是林北下午要期末考
I'll never let you get away with it!
我绝对不会放过你
Let's go back to study!
走 回去K书
I'll get you, you motherfucker!
相遇的到
(NO DISTINCTION OF CLASSES IN TEACHING.)
Miss Lin.
林同学
I know you're innocent.
我知道你是无辜的
If you to tell me
你只要告诉主任
what happened at the skating rink,
溜冰场当天的情况
you won't be punished.
没你的事儿
I...
那天
Cold.
感冒
I don't... remember
那天 发生什么事情
what happened when where who at all.
我不知道 不清楚 不记得了啦
Right. You went to indecent place
好 你翘课到不良场所
during school hours. Your punishment is
罚你爱校服务
10 hours of pool cleaning.
清理泳池十个小时
回去
Go back to your class.
Thank you, sir.
谢谢主任
What were you doing?
你们几个搞什么东西
School patrol skipped the class?
自己是纠察队还翘课
Hey, school patrol!
喂 你们这个臭纠察队的
Lin Truly!
林真心
How come you were in the office with Taiyu?
你怎么会和徐太宇被叫到训导处啊
Shhhh... for what?
嘘 · · ·什么
We can't what?
不能什么
I see! How many words?
哦 几个字 · · ·
Ouyang!
欧阳
Ouyang what?
欧阳什么啊
See...
看
your face.
脸 · · ·你
We can't let Ouyang see you.
欧阳不能看到你
Yes!
Yes
Lin Truly?
林真心
想不到你还满厉害的嘛
I didn't know you're actually pretty good.
I also like roller skating too.
我也很喜欢溜冰
Next time we can go together.
有机会一起去啊
Lin Truly.
林真心
Ouyang knows your name!
欧阳他知道你的名字耶
And even asked you out...
他还约你出去耶
Praised by Ouyang for skipping class...
翘课还被欧阳称赞
Strangely amazing.
这也太离奇了吧
Look, love fire is burning.
看爱火在燃烧
Love fire is bouncing.
爱火在跳跃
Warmly, our hearts
我们的心
embrace each other.
暖暖拥抱
I told my mom...
我妈知道了 · · ·
Did she give her approval?
她同意吗
Yes.
嗯
But...
可是
What if the teacher finds out
我们这样被老师发现
about us...?
怎么办
This is not allowed by the school.
学校是不准的
Don't worry.
不用担心
I am the father.
我是爸爸
I'll take the responsibility.
我会负责的
So glad you're here.
幸好有你在
You should go now!
回去吧
Others can come here anytime.
学生会中途跑出来
大家会起疑的
They'll find us suspicious.
Was someone here?
刚有人来过吗
What should we do?
怎么办
Will people find out about us?
我们的事不会被发现吧
We'll be fine.
没事的
Let's get out of here now.
我们赶快离开这里
What the fuck are you looking at!
看屁啊
Did you just try to drown yourself?
你刚是不是想淹死自己
Just for that prick?
就为了那个白痴
Then what on earth are you crying for?
那你在哭什么啊
You're the silly one...
你才白痴咧
Do you have it with you all the time?
你上课都随身携带这些哦
If you never had beer in your uniform...
没穿过高中制服 喝过几罐啤酒 长大以后
I'll regret in the future.
我会后悔
I got it.
知道啦
You wrote this?
这是你写的哦
You like Tao Minmin?
你喜欢陶敏敏
Dear Tao Minmin:
陶敏敏同学
When you were trying the hairpin yesterday,
昨天你在新学友书局试戴发夹
I really longed to touch...
一头乌黑的长发
the beautiful black hair of yours!
让人好想摸一下
You're so sick.
变态啊你
Because...
因为
It's so nice to meet you
认识你真好
do you know that?
知不知道
Quoting lyrics... you really suck.
烂透了还抄歌词
Now we're both kind of...
我们现在也算是
Association of the Dumped members.
失恋阵线联盟
For the first time I think you're clever.
第一次觉得你聪明
What?
干嘛
Let's help them break up.
一起让他们分手吧
If you help me chase Tao Minmin...
帮我追陶敏敏
wouldn't that make your Ouyang
你的欧阳
single again?
不就单身了吗
Sorry! Sorry!
对不起
Excuse me!
借过
Did you bring powdered milk and bottle?
你有带奶粉和奶瓶吗
Yeah.
有啊
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Sorry...
对不起哦
Mommy's late.
妈妈太晚来了
You must be starving.
你肚子一定饿坏了哦
Slowly... slowly.
乖 慢慢吃哦
Look at the eyes...
你看他的眼睛
So adorable.
好可爱哦
Just like you.
跟你好像哦
Should we take it to the vet for shots?
我们是不是要带它去打预防针
Yeah. Let's do it after school soon.
嗯 找天放学我们一起带它去
OK.
好
We misunderstood them.
哎哟 我们误会了啦
There is nothing between them.
他们根本就没什么
Just a puppy.
只是一起养狗啊
Having a dog now together means
虽然现在只是一起养狗
they'll walk the dog together. Get closer.
以后就会一起溜狗
Then the dog will have more puppies.
日久生情 狗又生狗
We can't let this happen.
不能让这种事发生
Say that again. What do you think of me?
再说一次你觉得我怎么样
You're tall...
又高
and cute...
又帅
If I look closely...
近看
You even look a bit like Andy Lau.
还有点像刘德华
Tao Minmin!
陶敏敏
The campus belle!
校花喔
So pretty!
好漂亮喔
《追梦人》凤飞飞
让青春吹动了你的长发让它牵引你的梦
不知不觉这城市的历史已记取了你的笑容
Our boss is hot!
老大好帅
红红心中蓝蓝的天是个生命的开始
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏同学
Wanna be my gal?
要不要做我女朋友
大嫂 · · ·
Say yes, Say yes.
春雨不眠隔夜的你曾空独眠的日子
今天的事谁敢说出去
If you dare to tell others what happened,
you are dead.
谁就死定了
Don't you tell others boss is dumped.
老大被甩谁敢说出去谁就死定了
Let me repeat.
我再说一次
Don't you tell others boss is dumped.
老大被甩谁敢说出去谁就死定了
What the fuck!
讲三小啊
Get lost!
滚
Quick!
快滚啦
Get out of there!
快滚
Hsu Taiyu...
徐太宇
I think... we should give up.
我看 我们还是放弃好了
Tao Minmin... will not be attracted by you.
陶敏敏 不会喜欢你这一型的啦
There is no such word like "give up".
我的字典里没有放弃
(REPORT STRAY DOGS TO HAVE THEM CAUGHT.)
As long as the dog is gone,
只要那只狗消失
they won't have excuse to meet each other.
他们就没有理由见面
Don't do silly things.
你不要冲动
I got it!
我有办法
Hurry up.
动作快
Puppy... they'll think you ran away...
狗狗 就让人家以为是你自己跑掉的
you're not stolen.
不是被偷走的哦
Hurry up!
快一点
Someone's coming.
有人来了啦
Such a stupid idea.
想什么烂招啊
Where can he go?
现在要带它去哪
Who's gonna take care of him?
谁有空照顾它啊
I thought you were really that cruel,
我还以为你真的那么狠
that you wouldn't care if he dies.
会不管它死活
Before you can find him a new owner,
找到人收养它以前
he's staying with you.
你给我带回家
Why the fuck do you pee...
怎么尿尿
Quick!
快点啦
Alright, alright.
哎哟 好啦 · · ·
What should we call him?
我们要叫它什么
What about...
叫
Andy?
"华仔"
You like it?
怎么样
No way.
我才不要咧
How can you humiliate my idol like this!
你怎么可以这样污蔑我的偶像啊
Besides...
而且
It's a she.
它是母的耶
ND the alphabets.
瓦斯的瓦
Anything wrong?
不行腻
ND... ND...
瓦仔 · · ·
See! She doesn't like it!
你看它不要啦
Why not?
为什么不要
Because you can't humiliate my idol!
因为你不可以这样污蔑我的偶像
Besides, she's a girl! -ND!
- 而且人家是少女 - 瓦仔
I'm gonna rub some dog pee on your head.
我拿尿摸你的头哦
- ND... - Hsu Taiyu!
- 瓦仔 - 徐太宇
(REPORT STRAY DOGS TO HAVE THEM CAUGHT.)
好像真的被捕狗大队抓走了
It seems like he's really caught...
昨天找了好久
I looked for her everywhere...
搞不好它被它主人找回去啦
Maybe she's just taken back by her owner.
值日生咧
Who's on duty today?
擦黑板啊
Clean it up!
我给你们方便你们当随便啊
You have no respect for your teacher...
起立
Stand up.
不用了
No need.
是谁
Who did this?
拿这种无聊的东西来诅咒别人
Cursing others with this silly stuff!
等一下到我办公室 自首
Come to my office and turn yourself in.
我不要求考托福
Excuse me.
报告
You should at least take exams.
至少你考试要出席嘛
You don't remember what I said?
老师的话都是从左耳进右耳出的吗
I got an anonymous letter saying you did it.
有同学匿名举发说幸运信是你寄来的
You know.
你知道
I remain unmarried for so many years,
我这么多年没有结婚
devoting myself to you...
牺牲奉献给你
I mean...
不是
to the school.
给学校
Can't you just do me a favor?
你就不能给我个面子吗
It's ok.
没关系
Tell me the truth...
你说实话
I'm very understanding.
老师很开明的
Listen...
我告诉你哦
If I find out that you're lying to me later,
你如果现在说谎后来被发现
I'll have no choice but to punish you.
那老师就只好处罚你了
I know who wrote it.
我知道信是谁写的
Wrote what?
什么信
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
You...
你
I wrote it.
是我写的
Very good.
非常好
Miss Lin.
林同学
You can go now.
你回去
Thank you.
是
I knew it!
我就知道是你
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I really wish it's not you again.
枉费我一直对你存着一丝希望
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
我跟你讲了一半你怎么可以走开
How can you leave in the middle of my talk?
Ms. Chen.
陈老师
Let me punish him first.
你先让我罚他
Mr. Wang, I haven't finished yet.
王老师我这边比较严重
Let me scold him first.
你让我先骂他
It's not a matter of...
不是什么比较严重还是
No, I was in the middle of scolding him.
没有我刚刚讲到一半我正在教训他
One thing at one time.
一个一个来
Don't rush.
不要急
You first.
你先
OK.
好
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why do you think the school still took you in
你觉得三年级才转学
even though it's your last year in high school?
为什么一高还愿意收你进来
Because you were in science honors class.
那是因为你国中念的是数理资优班
Even attended Science Olympiad competition.
还代表学校参加奥林匹亚的竞赛
What happened to you?
为什么你现在会变成这样
Have you heard of "The Tortoise and the Hare"?
听过龟兔赛跑的故事吗
And "Eradicating the Three Scourges".
还有改过自新的周处除三害
Do you know who's "Zhou Chu"?
周处知道是谁吗
Yeah.
知道
It's pronounced "Chu" not "Choo"...
那个字念处哦 · · ·不是处哦
Thank you.
谢谢
You...
其实
really didn't have to do that.
你可以不用帮我顶罪的
That's what a friend is for.
朋友就是要讲义气啊
It does me no harm anyway.
我又没差
One chain letter to me...
你一封信给我
One to "Asshole"...
一封信给王八蛋
Two others taken away by me...
两封都被我没收啦
Who got the last one?
你还有一封给谁
Tao Minmin...
陶敏敏
I really regret for it.
我也很后悔啊
That's why...
所以
You should work hard to get her!
你才要好好追人家嘛
Girls like her must have had
像她这样的女生啊
enough of compliments.
称赞一定听腻了
Why not write bad things about her
不如写一下她的缺点
to get her attention?
吸引她的注意力
For example...
譬如说
Thick waist...
腰粗
Huge butt...
屁股大
So fake when she talks...
讲话很假掰之类的
You sure?
你确定
Yeah.
嗯
And conclude it with...
然后最后再补一句
But still...
即使这样
I like you a lot.
我还是很喜欢你
Hey.
欵
Don't quote lyrics if you have no good idea.
没有灵感不要抄歌词啦
You can quote foreign poets' work.
可以抄外国诗人的作品
Who's gonna understand it?
谁看得懂
That's why it'll make you look mysterious.
就是看不懂才觉得你高深莫测啊
You sure?
你确定
Sure.
真的
Let me tell you.
我跟你说哦
Girls are so difficult to understand.
女生啊是很难捉摸地
When we say nothing's wrong...
我们说没事
it means something's wrong.
就是有事
When we say it's ok,
我们说没关系
it means it's not ok.
就是有关系
If we say...
如果我们今天说
I am fat...
我很胖
That means we hope you can tell us...
那就代表她希望你对她说
You're not fat at all.
她一点都不胖
That's the way...
陶敏敏
Tao Minmin thinks.
就是这样想的
(CHONGDE JUNIOR HIGH YEARBOOK)
(HSU TAIYU)
I'll do this.
我来做这个
You pick that one.
你选那一个
(OUYANG EXTRAORDINARY)
Don't stop.
你们继续练啊
Watch out.
看路喔
Ouyang Extraordinary...
欧阳非凡
You actually...
你其实
know Hsu Taiyu quite well.
跟徐太宇很熟
Right?
对不对
What?
怎样
Did you watch the Bulls vs. Lakers game?
昨天公牛跟湖人队的比赛有没有看
Of course.
当然有啊
Shit, what a dramatic victory.
大逆转
Jordan is God!
乔丹超神的啦
So dramatic!
大逆转啦
One-on-one if you dare.
有种来打赌啦
3 minutes.
三分钟
Whoever swims farther wins.
谁游得远谁就赢
Bring it on.
Who怕Who啊
C'mon.
来啊
A-yuan.
阿远
A-yuan...
阿远 · · ·
A-yuan.
阿远
Hsu Taiyu, don't go further.
徐太宇不要再过去了 徐太宇
Ma Suyuan.
马思远
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Taiyu thought the accident wouldn't have.
太宇觉得如果不是他答应跟阿远比赛
A-yuan.
阿远
Happened, if he didn't take the challenge.
或许意外就不会发生
That was the last time
从那天起
I saw Hsu Taiyu,
我就再也没看过徐太宇
before he transferred to First High.
直到他转学来到一高
He became someone I don't know.
变成了一个我不认识的人
Why don't we meet at Ice Palace,
干嘛不去冰宫
but here?
约在这里
You feel embarrassed?
怕丢脸
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Let's have a race.
我们来比赛
The winner can make a request.
赢的可以要求对方做一件事
Whoever crosses that line first wins.
谁先到那条线谁就赢
You can never beat me.
你赢不了我的啦
Stop or you'll kill yourself.
再这样下去会摔死
What's wrong with you?
你吃错药啊
When you saw me in the pool the other day,
那天你看到我在游泳池里
were you afraid that I'd die like Su-yuan,
你是不是怕我跟马思远一样
in front of your eyes.
在你面前溺死
Ouyang told me everything.
欧阳告诉我了
None of your business.
干你屁事啊
Who are you to shout at me?
你凭什么凶我啊
Who are you to hurt yourself like this?
你凭什么把自己搞成这个样子
It's also not easy for Ouyang, ok?
欧阳也很难过好不好
Ma Suyuan must be pissed off
马思远也一定很不爽
to see the way you are now.
你变成现在这个样子
Don't make me beat you!
不要以为我不敢揍你哦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
If I could do it over again,
如果刚刚重来一次
I'd still have a race with you.
我还是会和你比赛
If A-yuan could do it over again,
如果再重来一次
he'd still go into the sea.
阿远还是下海
But it's our own decision.
可是这是我们的决定
Not your responsibility.
不用你来负责啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
You agreed that
你刚答应过
the winner can make a request.
赢的人可以要求对方做一件事
What do you want?
什么
Can you...
你可不可以
be that Hsu Taiyu again?
做回徐太宇
Stand up!
起立
A...attention.
敬 · · ·敬礼
Good morning, sir.
老师好
Shut up!
上课
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇同学
Do you...
你
have any question?
有什么问题吗
Yes.
有
Which page are we at today?
今天上第几页
Chapter 7 on page 125.
第一百二十五页第七章
World War 2.
第二次世界大战
Hsu...
徐同学
You have
你翻的是
geography textbook in your hand.
地理课本耶
Chapter 7.
第七章
Page 125.
第一百二十五页
Take your textbook out!
课本拿出来啦
Those who don't have it...
没带课本的
go and sit next to those who do.
找有课本的一起看
Am I cute?
我可爱吗
Wow!
哇塞
Miss.
小姐
You look familiar...
你有点面熟
You are my high school...
你是我的高中
teacher.
老师
What's wrong with you today?
你今天干嘛
Going to temple festival?
要去庙会哦
Not really.
没有啦
I...
我
Hurry up!
快点啦
We need to secure our seats at McDonald's!
太晚去麦当劳会没位子
Temple festival is this way...
庙会在那边啦
Look at that guy...
你看那个男生
- So cute... - Look, it's him...
- 好帅哦 - 你看 就是他
so tall.
好高哦
So cute...
好帅哦
You idiot.
白痴哦
Look where you're going.
走路不看路
You got a hole in your brain?
脑袋有洞
It's fine.
没关系啦
Let's look for a seat first
我们先上去找位子
and order later.
等一下 下来点餐
You're gonna help me.
你要帮我喔
OK.
好啦
Here's what you ordered.
你的餐点都已经到齐了
Thanks.
谢谢
Have a nice meal.
祝你用餐愉快
Hello! Welcome!
你好欢迎光临
What would you like to order?
请问要点什么
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
He's studying there.
他在那边温书耶
It seems like he really changed.
看来他真的转性罗
Maybe he's here...
搞不好啊
because you come here often.
他是因为你常来这里他才来的呀
- Let's go... - What?
- 走啦 - 干嘛啦
Hey, she wants to talk to you.
欵 她有话跟你说
I'll find us a table.
我先去占位子
That seat is...
那个位子
Hsu...
徐同学
I heard you were in science honors class...
听说你以前是资优班的
If that's the case,
如果是这样的话
you should never give up.
你千万不要放弃
If there's something you don't understand,
课业上如果有什么问题
I can help you with it.
我可以帮你
Thanks.
谢啦
You asked me to give you my personal info.
你之前要我回的个人档案
You'll have it.
我会回
But...
但是
Don't mistake "Disney" for "Destiny" again.
下次不要再把"缘"写成"绿"了
Why "Destiny"?
什么缘啊
Disney is my pseudonym.
绿是我的笔名啊
What... were you... talking about?
刚 敏敏 找你干嘛
Nothing. They wanted to share the table.
没干嘛 想并桌
Study.
读书啊
Hsu Taiyu started to study hard.
徐太宇开始认真念书
Very hard.
很认真
Although I think it's because I woke him up,
虽然很想把这归功于我打醒他
the truth is...
但事实是
he did it for Minmin.
他为了敏敏
He wants to get into top 10
这次模拟考
in the coming mock exam.
他想考进英雄榜
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Did he come to see you?
他该不会是来看你的吧
Back then...
在那个年代
if a girl
一个女生
was willing to give you her personal info,
愿意回你她的个人资料
that means...
就代表
she didn't dislike you at all.
她对你还算有一点点好感
(THE PERSON I LIKE:)
Latest version of sample exams, good luck.
这最新的考古题 考试加油
Thank you.
谢谢
会的 谢谢老板
Ah.
啊
It's my hubby.
我的老公耶
When I grow up.
我长大以后啊
I will go to Taipei for your concert...
一定要去台北看你的演唱会
A piece of cake.
那有什么难的
One day I'll ask Andy Lau
以后我叫刘德华
to sing for you.
唱给你听
Really?
真的
Yeah right.
最好是啦
Hey! Don't touch it!
喂 不要碰
Let's go.
快走
If we add the two together...
这两个加在一起
Idiot.
笨蛋
Sin^2(X) + cos^2(X) = 1.
Sin X绝对值平方加Cos X绝对值平方
No exception.
永远等于一
What?
嗯
Look behind you.
看后面
Wow... when did Truly become so serious?
哇 林真心什么时候变那么认真
Something's wrong with Boss... hehe.
老大怪怪的哦
I live just down there.
我家就在前面
It's quite late.
已经很晚了
You should go home now.
你先走啦
Oh...
哦
It's ok.
没关系啊
If I linger a bit,
再一下
I might run into Tao Minmin.
搞不好会遇到陶敏敏
Oh...
哦
By the way.
对了
ND already learned to pee at the same spot.
瓦仔 现在已经会在固定的地方尿尿了
Thank God...
谢天谢地
she didn't grow into an idiot like you.
幸好没被你养笨
For me?
送我啊
I planned to give it to Tao Minmin.
本来是要送陶敏敏的
But it's so ugly and it's Andy Lau...
但是这么丑又是刘德华
better give it to you.
跟你比较配
Hey...
那个
tell me, for guys...
我问你哦
what's the definition of pretty girls?
男生 到底觉得什么样的女生漂亮
You mean what kind of girls Ouyang likes?
你想问欧阳喜欢怎么样的女生吧
Whatever.
随便啦
Anything.
都可以
He was crazy about Vivian Chow before.
他以前很迷周慧敏
What about you?
那你呢
Uchida Yuki is not bad.
内田有纪还不错
Sakai Noriko also.
还有酒井法子
Both Japanese?
都日本女生哦
Yes.
是
I want to learn roller skating.
我最近想学溜冰
Why so sudden?
干嘛突然想学
Because...
就 · · ·
Ouyang says he likes roller skating.
欧阳说他喜欢溜冰啊
You're pretty good... can you teach me?
你那么厉害 可以教我吗
Sure.
好啊
I want this.
这个
Hello, Mr. Tang.
汤叔叔好
Should I ask my bro to come down?
要不要帮你叫我哥下来
Where can I get the same look as yours?
去哪里才能弄得跟你一样啊
Go to hell and get reborn will be easier.
去地狱重新投胎比较快啦
Lin Truly, are you hitting puberty?
林真心 你思春哦
Don't be so mean.
你很坏
It's normal for girls to care their looks.
小女生都想要变漂亮啊
Let me help you.
姐姐帮你
Thank you sis.
谢谢大嫂
Are you alright?
你还好吗
Yeah, sprained my ankle, that's all.
没事只是练球扭到而已
Just need to ice it a bit.
冰敷一下就好了
Ouyang got injured. Does Truly know?
欧阳受伤了 真心知道吗
I don't know...
不知道
Let's tell her when she's here.
等她来我们赶快去跟她讲好了
Hey hey.
奇怪
Are you close friends of Ouyang's?
欧阳跟你们很熟吗
Ouyang!
欧阳
- Chiayi, you... - Calm down.
- 沈家仪你真的 - 息怒 · · ·
Are you alright?
你还好吧
Yeah.
还好
Wow it swells so much.
哇这肿得很厉害
No way, we must heat it.
不行 这一定要热敷一下
Ice it.
是冰敷啦
Heat it! Were you there in health class?
是热敷啦 你有没有在上健康教育
Hey...
这个
I always ice with this when I'm injured.
我受伤的时候都用这个冰敷
Convenient and tasty.
方便又好吃
Thanks.
谢啦
看样子我不用去保健室了
Guess I don't have to visit health center.
I'll go back to class now.
我先去上课
You look cute today.
今天满可爱的
The hairstyle suits you.
这发型很适合你
Good luck with your exam.
段考加油
Wow!
哇
So cute.
可爱哦
Lin Truly, you are so pretty.
林真心你好漂亮哦
I want to look like you!
我也想跟你一样
He said you're cute!
被称赞罗
Did you put on makeup?
你是不是有化妆啊
Hsu Taiyu got 10th place in the mock exam
那次三年级模拟考
among all 3rd year students.
徐太宇进了英雄榜第十名
While the whole school was still in shock,
在全校为他震惊时
the new director arrived.
新的训导主任来了
Littering.
乱丢垃圾
Which eye of yours saw that I littered?
你哪只眼睛看到我乱丢垃圾
You are the litter.
你就是垃圾
Director Chuan said...
全主任说
Everyone in class 317...
你们317的人
is a piece of shit.
都是垃圾
Fuck! What the hell!
靠北哦
School regulation says "no hair coloring".
校规明订 禁止学生染发
The new director hates people who break the rules.
我们全主任最讨厌破坏校规的人
Excuse me.
报告
Hsu Taiyu from class 317.
317的徐太宇
Finally.
终于见面了
You'd better be good until you graduate.
你最好在毕业之前安分一点
Otherwise I'll kick you out of the school
否则三大过一满
once you're cited with 3 serious demerits.
我一定退你学
As you wish.
退就退啊
I'll do my best.
我会尽力而为
Because people like you
因为像你们这种人
do not deserve education at all.
根本就不配受教育
Stand up.
起立
Who got first place in the exam this time?
你们班这次段考第一名的同学是谁
Please stand up.
请起立
Let's give him a big hand.
大家掌声鼓励
Good job.
真的很厉害
So good that I have to ask Hsu...
厉害到我想请问一下徐同学
how did you cheat in the exam?
这次考试你是怎么作弊来的
I asked people to give you a big hand
我刚才叫大家鼓掌
to see if you know what is shame!
是想看看你有没有羞耻心
You just talked, stand up!
那位讲话的同学站起来
Sir.
报告主任
I didn't talk.
我没有讲话
I have eyes to judge that.
有没有讲话我自己有眼睛看
Did you help him...
这次考试
in the exam?
你有没有帮忙他
Can someone come forward and testify that.
有哪位同学可以出来作证
Hsu Taiyu cheated.
徐太宇作弊
No one wants to tell the truth, huh?
没有人肯说实话是不是
Now...
现在
All of you, go to the running track.
全班到操场跑步
Stand up!
起立
I know you dislike me...
你看我不顺眼
but it has nothing to do with them!
干他们屁事啊
Leave them alone.
要罚就罚我一个
Fine.
好
Want to play the hero?
爱逞英雄嘛
I'll leave all 50 rounds to you.
那就五十圈都让你跑
Run to your heart's content.
跑个够
Director Chuan must be sick. So strict.
全主任有病吧 服仪抓这么严
Demerit for skirts above the knees.
对啊 裙子没到膝下就被记过
A lap is 400 meters!
这一圈有四百公尺
I heard that Hsu already finished 35 rounds.
对啊 他已经跑第三十五圈了
I heard that he cheated in the exam
听说徐太宇考试作弊
and started a battle with the director.
跟主任杠上了
He's punished to run 50 rounds.
所以被罚跑操场五十圈
He's not that kind of person.
他才不是那种人
Minmin, Chiayi is bullshiting.
陶敏敏你不要听沈家仪乱讲
Lin Truly...
林真心
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why don't you tell the truth?
你为什么不说实话
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Excuse me.
借过一下
Director.
主任
Hsu Taiyu really didn't cheat.
徐太宇同学真的没有作弊
I can testify for him.
我可以作证
He really studied very hard.
他真的很努力的念书
You should stay away from people like him.
你们升学班的最好少跟那种人混在一起
Tell him,
告诉他
if he can't finish, 1 more demerit for him.
今天要是没跑完我一定记他一支大过
Plus one-week suspension from school.
外加禁学一个礼拜
Let him reflect on himself at home.
让他在家好好反省
How's your boss doing?
你们老大现在还好吗
Dunno...
不知道
He doesn't answer on his pager.
call机他都没回
I heard that the school festival next week
听说下礼拜校庆
might be cancelled by the director.
主任想要取消耶
He said we students don't study enough.
是说什么学生太沉迷外务
What the fuck is he thinking!
听他放屁啊
Students also deserve human rights!
学生就不能够有人权吗
The authority shouldn't let him bully us!
学校怎么可以让他这样欺负我们
Of course not!
当然不可以
We'll let the authority hear our voice
下个礼拜校庆
at the school festival next week.
要让学校听到我们的声音
Let him know he can't do whatever he likes.
让主任知道他不能为所欲为
Let's do it!
好
Sorry.
不好意思
- Please stand up for our rights - Please.
- 同学 站出来 - 麻烦你 拜托
Please, the revolt needs your support.
同学 一高起义需要你的支持
The revolt needs your support.
一高起义需要你的支持
Please have a look...
同学 · · ·请看一下 · · ·
Please, please have a look.
同学 · · ·看一下
Please support First High's revolt.
一高起义请支持
一高起义请多支持
Please, please have a look.
同学 · · ·你看一下
We really really
你们的支持
need your support.
对我们真的很重要
Don't take it.
不要啦
You're done if the director knows.
被主任知道就完了耶
Leave it to me.
交给我
Hand it out over there. You, there.
你去发那边 你去那边
You're openly instigating others to revolt,
你这是公然煽动同学
violating the regulations,
违纲乱纪
humiliating your teachers.
侮辱师长
Everyone who helped you now has a demerit.
你害那些帮你的同学现在全部都被记过了
Do your parents know what you're doing?
你爸妈知道你干这事儿吗
You brought disgrace on your parents.
你让父母蒙羞
You brought shame on them.
你丢你爸妈的脸
The teacher said Hsu is a gangster.
老师说那个徐太宇是流氓学生耶
He's not even allowed to go to school!
学校不让他上学你看他有多坏
You completely destroyed my reputation.
我的脸都被你丢光了啦
You... go upstairs and write your confession.
你 · · ·现在给我上去写悔过书
You're grounded for two days.
两天不准出门
Now!
现在
How embarrassing.
真是丢人现眼
I was scolded by the teacher on the phone.
老师今天打电话来我就站在这里给他骂耶
I...
我
- Hello? - This is Truly's cram school.
- 喂 - 我是林真心的补习班
Lin Truly is busy now.
林真心没空啦
Hey...
欵
It's a guy...
男生耶
Hello?
喂
It's you again!
又是你
Never call again!
以后不准打电话来
You are so rude.
你这个人怎么那么没有教养啊
If he calls again, let me pick it up.
如果再打来我接
Must be him.
一定是他
Pretending to be cram school staff.
装补习班
Lin Truly.
林真心
Don't call me these two days.
这两天你先不要打电话过来
What's wrong?
怎么了
What happened?
发生什么事
Nothing's wrong. Bye.
我没事 先这样
Are you ok?
没事吧
It's so late... you must be going to bed?
这么晚 你应该要睡了吧
I'm just stopping by.
我只是刚好经过
Well...
那
I'm leaving then.
我走罗
Hold on.
你等一下
ND.
瓦仔
Are you alright?
你还好吗
Never knew I can be suspended from school.
第一次知道可以被禁学不用上课
Feels awesome.
超爽
I mean... you passed out at school...
我是说 那天在学校昏倒
It's just heat stroke.
中暑而已啊
Nothing fatal.
又不会死
Why are you suddenly grounded?
你怎么突然被禁足
Anyone can be grounded for knowing you, ok?
任何人被发现认识你都会被禁足 好吗
What brought you here?
你怎么会来啊
Because you said...
因为你说过
When a girl says "I'm ok", she's not ok.
女生说没关系就是有关系
Nothing's wrong means something's wrong.
我没事 就是有事啊
Do you want to come to a place with me?
要不要去一个地方
What?
蛤
Wait here.
你在这里等我一下
Since I discovered this place,
我发现这里以后
I've been coming here at midnight a lot.
就常常半夜来溜
You want to learn roller skating, right?
你不是想学溜冰
Let me tell you how not to fall.
告诉你不要摔倒的秘诀是什么
What's the tip?
是什么
Don't...
就是
be afraid of falling.
不要怕摔倒
It can't get worse than falling.
最惨就是摔倒而已
The important thing is...
重要的是
why are you here.
你为什么来这里
Thank you.
谢谢
What?
干嘛
On the day of school festival,
趁着校庆
let's give out awards to the top 10 students
现在我们来表扬
of the mock exam of 3rd grade.
三年级这一次模拟考前十名的同学
1st place.
第一名
Class 301, Ouyang Extraordinary.
三年一班欧阳非凡
2nd place.
第二名
Class 301, Li Chiming.
三年一班李智明
3rd place.
第三名
Class 302, Yang Chiaying.
三年二班杨佳颖
4th place.
第四名
Class 303, Liao Chide.
三年三班廖志德
10th place.
第十名 · · ·
5th place. Class 304, Tao Minmin.
第五名 三年四班陶敏敏
6th place.
第六名
Class 301, Lin Bingsheng.
三年一班林秉盛
7th place.
第七名
Class 309, Chen Yuting.
三年九班陈钰婷
8th place.
第八名
Class 306, Li Chengfu.
三年六班李城甫
It's coming...
来了 · · ·
9th place.
第九名
Class 303, Wang Aiwei.
三年三班王艾伟
Get ready. Get ready.
准备 准备
Up to the stage, now!
上台 上台
Please come up to the stage.
以上九位同学上台领奖
You might be wondering...
你们可能觉得很奇怪
why there are only 9 of them.
为什么没有第十名
Because...
因为
the school denounces cheating in exams.
学校严厉谴责考试作弊的行为
We human beings must have a sense of shame.
做人要有羞耻心
You should never think those sneaky,
不要以为偷鸡摸狗
shameful behavior of yours
干了不要脸的事情
will not be found out.
不会被发现
Hsu of Class 317, I'm talking about YOU.
三年十七班徐太宇我说的就是你
What rubbish?
胡说什么
Mind your own business!
看什么
Sir.
报告
We're giving out awards now,
这位同学
if you want to talk, we'll...
我们现在要颁奖 有什么事情我们到 · · ·
Director.
主任
I have something serious to report now.
我有非常严重的事情必须立刻报告
My skirt is 3cm higher than my knee.
我的裙子比膝下短三公分
My socks are not 100% white.
袜子没有全白
My jacket's zipper never pulled high enough.
外套拉链从来没有拉到学号高度
Please punish me, sir.
请主任处份
All these are not important now.
现在这些不重要
We'll take our time to punish her later.
待会我们再来好好处罚这位同学
If none of these rules is important,
如果这些都不重要
why should we follow them?
我们为什么要遵守
Therefore,
所以
please cite me with an admonition
根据校规
according to school regulations.
请记我警告
Director.
报告主任
I cheated in exams.
我作弊
Please cite me with a major demerit
考试舞弊根据校规必须记大过
according to school regulations.
请主任处分
Ouyang.
欧阳同学
Don't play with your future.
不要拿自己的前途开玩笑
You're applying for Taiwan University,
尤其你申请台大保送
Your discipline record can't be affected.
操行不能受影响
Besides, we know very well. You're smart.
况且学校很清楚
It's not possible that you...
依你的实力不可能
Why not?
为什么不可能
If Director Chuan can say that Hsu Taiyu
如果全主任可以说三年十七班
of Class 317 cheated on the exam,
徐太宇同学作弊
I can say I did it.
我现在说有
And what I say counts.
那就是有
Alright.
好
Since Ouyang confessed his crime bravely,
既然欧阳同学有勇气自首
I'll make sure he gets a major demerit.
那我绝对严格执行记过
Director Chuan...
主任
We need further discussion.
这事还要再讨论
Principal, Ouyang just...
校长 欧阳同学他
Director.
报告主任
I'm in shorts while it's not a P.E. class.
我在非体育课的时候穿短裤
Please cite me with an admonition.
请记我警告
Director.
报告主任
You're my chocolate.
你是我的巧克力
I'm disrespectful to teachers.
我态度轻浮随便
Please cite me with an admonition.
请记我警告
Director.
报告主任
I spread obscene ideas.
我传播猥亵思想
Please cite me with a minor demerit.
请记我一支小过吧
Director.
报告主任
Eat shit!
你吃屎吧
Sorry I humiliated teachers.
对不起我侮辱师长
Please cite me with a major demerit.
请记我大过一支
Director.
报告主任
I... I have a girlfriend.
我 · · ·有女朋友
Bullshit.
屁啦
Director.
报告主任
I brought my pager to school.
我私带BBCall到学校
Please cite me with an admonition.
请记我警告一支
Director.
报告主任
I didn't flush the toilet.
我上厕所没冲水
Director.
报告主任
I'm not wearing underpants.
我没穿内裤
I play Game Boy in class.
我上课打电动
I sleep in class...
我上课睡觉
I have a boyfriend...
我有男朋友
Director.
主任
You said students should be like students.
你说学生要有学生的样子
But neither exams nor school regulations
但是分数和校规
can define us.
都不能定义我们
Those with good scores can make mistakes.
成绩好的学生也会犯错
Those who made a mistake can improve.
曾经犯错的有一天也会变好
Whether we're good or bad is not up to you.
是好是坏不是你说了算
Only we know who we are.
只有我们自己知道我是谁
Only we can decide the way we are.
只有我们自己能决定自己的样子
Alright. Alright.
好 好 好
Calm down everyone.
同学冷静
Today is the 54th anniversary of our school.
今天是我们五十四周年校庆
First High is always a liberal school.
一高一直自诩是间自由开放的学校
I'm here to promise you that, we'll discuss,
校长在这边承诺同学
improve ourselves and proceed accordingly.
会检讨改进做出相对的处理
The long-waited water balloon fight
那么同学们期待已久的水球大战
officially starts now.
现在正式开打
We didn't know until years later...
很多年以后我们才知道
the first person you throw your balloon at,
让你第一个砸下水球的人
is not someone you dislike,
不是你讨厌他
but someone you can't take your eyes off.
而是你的眼里 只有他
Hey! You meant it.
喂 你很故意耶
That's not true.
没有啊
Just to wait for Dahe and Small.
等一下大贺跟小只嘛
Are you tired?
累不累
Just to keep your hands warm.
这样手比较不会冷
I picked your key.
我钥匙抽到你耶
We must be meant for each other, right?
我们是不是很有缘啊
Meant for hell.
缘你妈啦
You're going so slow on purpose...
你故意骑这么慢
is it because you want us to be alone?
是不是为了想要跟我独处啊
Boss...
老大
Sakuraki... wait for me!
樱木 等等我
Follow the beat!
不要抢拍
Truth or Dare.
真心话大冒险
Ouyang...
欧阳
Are you seeing someone?
你有没有喜欢的人啊
Is she here?
在不在现场
Yes, she's here.
有 在现场
Wow! Mr. Straight-A confessed his love.
哇 模范生表白了
Boss, boss.
老大 · · ·
So... are you seeing someone? Is she here?
那 你有喜欢的人吗
Is she here?
她在现场吗
Yes, she's here.
有 她在现场
Who's that?
谁啊
Boss, tell me... please.
好想知道老大
Hurry up...
快点
Oh... Lin Truly.
哦 林真心
Are you seeing someone?
你有喜欢的人吗
Is he here?
他在现场吗
Hold on.
欵 等一下
Is this bottle...
这个瓶子
pointing closer to Tao Minmin?
是不是比较靠近陶敏敏啊
Boss.
老大 · · ·
Ask again. Ask again.
你再问一次 快点 · · ·
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏
Ask again. Ask again.
再问一次 · · ·
Minmin, Minmin.
敏敏 · · ·
Have you ever sent out chain letters?
你有寄过幸运信吗
What the hell is that?
你问这什么问题啊
Drink it.
自己喝啦
How did you know that Minmin sent me
你怎么知道
the chain letter and reported me?
敏敏寄给我幸运信 还跟老师举发我
Who knows that you're sending chain letters?
谁会知道班上有人在写幸运信啊
Must be the person who sent it to you.
当然是一开始写信给你的人
Tao Minmin received exactly the same letter
如果陶敏敏收到过跟自己一模一样的信
she sent out. That's why she knows
她才会知道
one of the classmates who received
一定她自己害的同学里面
her letter sent it to the teacher.
有人把幸运信寄给老师
I guess you're the only one who knows.
我猜她五封信里面
Wang Baidan among the 5 receivers.
只有你认识王白丹
I never thought
没想到
she would do something like this.
她会做这种事
I thought she was perfect.
我还以为她很完美
Now I think your personality is better.
我现在倒觉得她个性没有你好
And if I look closely...
认真看
she's not that much prettier than you.
好像没比你漂亮多少
Maybe just this much prettier.
大概只有漂亮这么 多
Which university do you want to go to?
你大学想要考哪里啊
Taiwan University, I guess.
台大吧
And you?
你呢
Same for me.
我也想上台大
But... I don't think I can get in.
可是 考不上吧
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
If...
如果
we end up going to different universities,
我们没有考到同一个地方
can you promise me?
你可不可以答应我
That...
以后
you'll continue to study hard and graduate.
还是好好读书 好好毕业
That you'll never fight again...
不要再打架
That you'll never...
不要
worry people who care about you.
让在乎你的人担心
Ok.
嗯
I promise you.
我答应你
What about you?
那你呢
Yes?
嗯
If I go to somewhere very far from you,
如果以后 我跟你念的学校离的很远很远
can you promise me?
你可不可以答应我
That sesame dressing and noodles
麻酱面 麻酱跟面
will never be mixed together.
还是要分开
Not funny.
白痴
I'm serious.
我是说真的
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Shooting star!
有流星
Make a wish.
快许愿
Chain letters can never bring good luck.
幸运信从来就不能带来好运
But on that night,
但那个晚上
I felt...
我却觉得
I found my luck.
我找到了我的幸运
Welcome to the.
欢迎收看
"Superstitious Show".
鬼话连篇
Mom! It's starting!
妈 开始了啦
Let's have a look at this weird picture.
好我们在来看一张奇怪的照片
A group of high school students went
哦这是上个月一群高中生
camping last month and took this photo.
去山上露营拍到的哦
Let's hear what the expert has to say.
我们先来看看专家怎么说
The student in the photo
照片中的男同学
became translucent.
出现了半透明的现象
If we look at the supernatural aspect of it,
我们从灵学的角度去研判
it's obvious that
明显的呢感应到
this photo
这张照片
is full of supernatural energy.
充满着灵异的能量
I suggest the student
我建议这位同学
visit temples guarding land and underworld
要去拜土地公和城隍爷
- to remove ill fortune. - Go home soon.
- 来消灾祈福 - 早点回家
Take care.
小心安全
Thanks.
谢啦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I finally...
终于
got you.
堵到你了厚
The bell has rung.
同学打钟罗
Hand in your paper.
交卷
Sakuraki said that.
我听樱木说啊
Hsu hasn't come to school for a week.
徐太宇已经一个礼拜没有来学校上课
He's even absent from the mock exam.
连模拟考他都缺考
Did you watch the TV show last week?
你们有没有看上个礼拜的玫瑰之夜啊
Maybe something really happened to him?
他不会真的出什么事了吧
I don't think so.
不会吧
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why didn't you take the mock exam?
你为什么没来学校模拟考
None of your business.
不关你的事
Why did you... fight again?
为什么 又打架
For no reason.
没有为什么
They wanted to fight.
他们想打
So I fought with them.
我就陪他们打
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
我再也不想理你了
When a girl says
当一个女生说
"nothing's wrong", something must be wrong.
我没事就是有事
"I'm ok" means "I'm not ok."
没关系就是有关系
We didn't know until
很久很久以后
long after that:
我们才知道
When a girl says.
当一个女生说
"I don't want to talk to you anymore."
她再也不理你
She doesn't really hate you.
不是真的讨厌你
Instead she cares about you...
而是她很在乎你
very
非常
very much.
非常 在乎你
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
Thank you...
谢谢
This is...
这是
Boss brought it back himself.
是老大亲手去搬的
We don't know what he's been busy with,
最近他不知道在忙什么
but he still remembers your birthday.
但是他还是记得明天是你的生日哦
And this!
还有这个
Boss said that you shouldn't listen to it
老大特别交代
before the university entrance exam.
联考过后才能够听
There must be something special in it.
一定有什么Special的
When you see boss in school tomorrow,
明天去学校
don't forget to thank him.
记得好好跟老大说声谢谢
Bye bye.
再见
Lin Truly.
林真心
Today's your birthday, let's go to...
今天是你生日我看我们放学去吃
Chicken House...
香鸡城
Great! Hand-shredded chicken set for me.
好 · · ·我要吃那个手扒鸡套餐
I'm gonna have two.
我要吃两只
Look! It's Hsu Taiyu.
是 317 的徐太宇耶
Who is he looking for?
他要找谁啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Lin Truly...
哦 林真心哦
go go go.
赶快去
He came to see you, Lin Truly.
特地来班上找你哦 林真心
Happy birthday...
过生日哦
So romantic!
好浪漫喔
Last night...
昨天
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh. You're welcome.
哦 没什么
Did you like it?
那东西你喜欢吗
Of course!
嗯 当然啊
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
What did you want to say?
啊 找我什么事啊
Small and Meimei are waiting for me.
小只她们还在等我
We're discussing where to go for dinner.
我们在讨论晚上要去哪里庆生
Do you want to join us?
你要一起来吗
By the way.
啊 对了
Please write this for me.
这个毕业纪念册你拿去写
Make sure you...
要照
fill in your personal info
第一页那样
like the sample on page 1.
填完个人资料哦
What's wrong?
嗯
Taiyu...
太宇
Were you looking for me?
你刚到班上来找我
For what?
做什么
Wait for me here.
你等我一下
So you came for Minmin?
你是来找敏敏的啊
You should've told me...
早说嘛
you came for Minmin to...
你找敏敏 · · ·
She told me she likes me.
她跟我告白
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
怎么现在才告诉我
Hmmm... congratulations.
嗯 恭喜啊
What a surprise!
吓我一跳
I even helped you chase her for so long.
亏我帮你追她追那么久
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Finally.
修成正果
Thank you.
谢谢你
It'll definitely work out
你跟欧阳
between Ouyang and you.
一定也没问题的
Good luck.
祝你好运
Thanks.
嗯
I'm... really happy for you.
我 真的很替你开心
It's pouring rain...
雨很大了耶
Goodbye.
再见
Come with us...
一起走啊
It's ok. Thanks.
不用啦 谢谢
Look! It says that
喂 大成报说啊
Andy Lau has a girlfriend!
刘德华现在有女朋友耶
What? It must be rumor.
蛤 这一定是假消息啦
Andy Lau will never get married.
刘德华是永远不会结婚的
We all dreamed of marrying our idols,
就像我们都幻想能嫁给偶像
That must be a rumor.
假的啦假的啦
But in reality...
但现实是
Of course Andy Lau belongs to someone else.
刘德华终究是别人的
Same for our first love.
我们的初恋
Of course we can't beat girls like Minmin.
注定会输给像陶敏敏那样的女孩
Morning.
早
Don't cry.
不要难过啦
Morning.
早安
Going abroad as soon as he got you.
追到手就出国念书
He was just fooling you.
根本在耍你啊
In the end...
果然哦
we shouldn't have trusted a freak who
要求麻酱跟面分开的怪咖
separates sesame dressing from noodles.
还是不能相信啦
I heard that Director Chuan
我听说啊
caught him fighting with others
全主任抓到他在校外械斗
and wanted to kick him out of the school.
要他退学
That's why his dad sent him abroad.
所以他爸才把他送出国
What? Really?
蛤 真的假的
Shhh...
欵 · · ·嘘
Quiet. Here she comes.
不要说了 她来了
What are you talking about?
在聊什么啊
We are here to study.
我们是来看书的
- Yes - Right.
- 嗯 - 对
Back then, there was no facebook.
在那个没有脸书的年代
12,000km means
一万二仟公里
parting for good.
就是永别的距离
But sometimes
只是有时候
there were some moments,
在某个瞬间
I felt he would appear
会觉得好像下一秒
the next second.
他就会出现
Are you ok?
没事吧
Be careful.
小心点
This is the ultimate note.
大补帖给你
等你考完
Let's go roller skating
after you finish the exam.
我们去溜冰
Or...
还是
do you want to go to the movies?
你想看电影
Ah! Stephen Chow's ”Monkey King” is on again.
啊 周星驰那部西游记上二轮了
I want to watch it again.
我想再看一次
Last time...
上次
I didn't quite get it.
好像看不太懂
Hsu Taiyu left.
徐太宇离开了
My life
我的生活
seemed to be back to the same old.
好像回到遇见他之前的原点
But I know
但我知道
because of him.
因为他
I am...
我才是
who I am now.
现在的我
(TO: LIN TRULY)
(林真心 收)
好
OK.
(YOU'RE PRETTY. CAN I BE YOUR FRIEND?)
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Finally done with the entrance exam.
考完联考了
Thanks.
谢啦
I think...
这次
I did pretty well in math.
数学成绩还不错
Thanks for the ultimate note.
多亏你整理给我的大补帖
Did you...
那
listen to the tape?
你听了吗
The one Taiyu gave you.
太宇送你的那卷卡带
I promised him
提醒你这个
to remind you of this.
也是我答应他的事
It's a shame that
只是很可惜
the ending
结局
isn't like what he thought.
不是他想的那样
Hsu Taiyu! Shooting star!
徐太宇 有流星
Make a wish!
快许愿
You know that I heard it, right?
你不会以为我会装没听到吧
The person you like...
你喜欢的人
is here.
在现场
In the beginning,
一开始
I thought whoever believed in chain letters
看到有人相信幸运信这种事
was either an idiot
我觉得他应该不是白痴
or an idiot.
就是弱智
But later I realized that
可是后来发现
she's simply a very kind person.
她只是一个很善良的人
To whoever received this:
收到这封信的人
I am really really sorry.
真的对不起
I was forced to send it...
其实 我也是逼不得已的
You might be hit by a car,
你可能会被车撞
get cancer...
得绝症
or... lose your family.
或 · · ·或家破人亡
But...
但
I'm sure you'll turn ill luck into good,
你一定会逢凶化吉
have a successful life,
一帆风顺
become wealthy.
年年有余
That's why I wanted to know her.
所以说要跟他做朋友
Let's be friends.
我们 交个朋友吧
I was serious.
我是认真的
What?
蛤
I thought chasing girls...
本来我觉得追女生
was that simple.
不就这么一回事
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏同学
Wanna be my gal?
要不要做我女朋友
Say yes! Say yes!
大嫂 · · ·
Later I realized...
后来才明白
if you really like someone...
如果你真的喜欢一个人
you might not even notice it.
是不知不觉
I was actually super nervous that day.
那一天我其实超紧张
I have to thank that car.
感谢那辆车
The moment I held her in my arm...
搭住她肩的那一刻
I realized that I never knew...
我第一次发现
my heart... can beat so fast.
心 可以跳这么快
What... were you... talking about?
刚 敏敏找你干嘛
I didn't want her to misunderstand.
怕她误会所以不想说太多
But somehow...
但是不知道为什么
at the end of that day
那一天到最后
she didn't seem happy.
她好像不太开心
When you like someone
原来喜欢一个人
and see her walk to someone she likes,
当你看到她走向她喜欢的人
you'd suddenly realize that
才突然发现
you treat her badly just because
你对她很坏
you want to get a bit closer to her.
只是为了想跟她更靠近一点
For me?
送我哦
You'll keep every word she said
她说的每一句话
in mind.
你都会放在心上
Nothing's wrong.
我没事
Bye.
先这样
When we say nothing's wrong...
我们说没事
it means something's wrong.
就是有事
When we say it's ok,
没关系
it means it's not ok.
就是有关系
Are you ok?
没事吧
I didn't know that when I'm in love,
原来喜欢一个人
I actually have no courage to tell her.
会没有勇气告诉她
On that night,
那个晚上
I made a wish upon a shooting star.
我向流星许愿
I wish I was also
希望她的愿望里
in her wish.
也有我
Even if I know it's someone else
即使我知道能让她快乐的
who could make her happy...
是另一个人
Sometimes... she still pretends to be ok
她 有时候明明很难过
even when she feels very sad.
还会逞强说自己没事
Spending 5 minutes deciding what to have,
早餐会犹豫五分钟
before choosing the same old raddish cake.
但最后还是选择萝卜糕
She doesn't watch where she's going.
她常常走路不看路
Please watch her at all times.
要记得 时刻看着她
Are you ok?
没事吧
She wants to go to Taiwan University,
想考台大
but she's really bad at math.
但是数学很差
She likes roller skating,
喜欢溜冰
loves Stephen Chow's films...
爱看周星驰
Let's go roller skating
等你考完试
after you finish the exam.
我们去溜冰
She...
她
likes you very much.
她很喜欢你
I didn't know that
我后来才知道
he disappeared for so long
他失踪那么久
was because he had a surgery.
是在医院开刀
Do you see that?
看到没有
You have a blood clot here.
脑膜下腔这边有一点血块
This is why you passed out when running.
这就是造成你跑步晕倒的原因
It might be caused by the car accident.
可能是之前车祸的后遗症
That sounds really bad!
这么严重哦
Should've charged the driver more.
早知道跟撞我的人多收一点医药费
You really should.
你的确应该
You'll need a surgery
这要动刀
and stay in the hospital.
还要住院
Your family has to come to look after you.
通知一下你的家人来照顾你
He wanted me to keep the secret.
他希望我保密
I guess...
我想
he didn't want you to blame yourself.
他一定是担心你 因为那场车祸自责
His family told the school long time ago
他们家很早就跟学校联络
that they wanted to take him to the U.S..
要他移民美国
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇同学
I hope you can start over again
我希望你到美国之后
after arriving in the U.S..
能够重新开始
Director.
主任
Thank you.
谢谢
Sakuraki said that.
我听樱木说啊
Hsu hasn't come to school for a week.
徐太宇已经一个礼拜没有来学校上课了
He's even absent from the mock exam.
连模拟考他都缺考
Aren't you moving to the U.S. soon?
之后开完刀你不是要跟家人移民了吗
Why are you still studying this?
还读这些干嘛什么
Because...
因为
I made a promise.
我答应了一个人
Can you...
你可不可以
be that Hsu Taiyu again?
做回徐太宇
Why did you... fight again?
为什么 又打架
For no reason.
没有为什么
They wanted to fight.
他们想打
So I fought with them.
我就陪他们打
Sorry for coming here so late
不好意思这么晚来买东西
and asking that standee for free.
还要求加送人型立牌
Sorry.
歹势啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I finally
终于
got you.
堵到你了厚
It's Andy Lau!
刘德华耶
Don't you motherfucker dodge!
他妈的你还敢闪
You want me to invite your gal for tea?
不要逼我请你马子喝茶
She always goes to
她放学
that teashop to study.
会去小歇看书嘛
Class...
三年
304...
四班
Lin... Tru... ly...
林 真 心
Don't you ever touch her!
你敢动她试看看
It depends on whether you're a good boy...
那要看你今天听不听话
whether you let me beat you... up...
让我打得爽不爽啊
Lin Truly.
林真心
Now you're with the person you like, right?
你现在应该跟喜欢的人在一起了吧
I won Tao Minmin's heart.
我追到陶敏敏
You won Ouyang's.
你追到欧阳
We fulfilled the promise
完成
we made in the beginning.
我们一开始说好的约定
I guess...
我想
this is the only
这是我能为你做的唯一
and the last thing I could do for you.
也是最后一件事情
Lin Truly.
林真心
Although you're short
虽然你又矮
and stupid.
又笨
And you even like someone else.
还喜欢别的男生
Even so...
即使这样
I still...
我还是
like you a lot.
很喜欢你
Lin Truly.
林真心
If you already listened to the whole tape,
如果你听完这卷录音带
just look up at the sky.
就抬头看看天上
Then I will know
因为那时候我会知道
I'm looking at the same starry sky
原来我喜欢的那个女孩
as the girl I like.
正在看一样的星空
I Love You.
Aqui te amo（西班牙文：我爱你）
(THE PERSON I LIKE: HSU TAIYU)
(我喜欢的人是徐太宇)
You were always wondering...
你常常幻想
what your future would be like.
长大后的你会是怎么样的
Now... I can give you the answer.
现在 我可以告诉你了
Give me the salary
给我该给的薪水
and the holidays I deserve,
放我该放的假
or let me quit.
不然你让我辞职吧
I don't need to waste my life
人不需要在一个 不在乎你是谁的地方
in a place where no one cares who I am.
浪费自己的人生
Truly! Truly!
真心姐 · · ·
What the fuck!
哇靠
Handwritten resignation letter... so ancient.
这年代还有人手写辞职信啊
We'd probably just send emails.
我们顶多发发mail
Who dares to
哪敢
do this.
这样啊
You're so cool.
你太棒了
Sometimes...
有些事
it's still way cooler to
还是用我们的方式
do it our way.
比较屌
By the way.
还有
All of you have a share
我的业绩奖金
of my performance bonus.
你们通通都有份
Yay!
呀
So you quit?
所以你辞职了
How can you be so immature?
你怎么会这么不成熟啊
Why can't you just be flexible?
为什么不懂得变通一下
Everyone can stick to it, why can't you?
大家都能继续做下去为什么只有你不行
Do you remember that
你还记不记得有一次
once I asked you to pay card bill for me?
我叫你去帮我缴信用卡费
It's true I gave you the bill quite late.
我是很晚才给你帐单没错
But it doesn't mean you could...
但是这也不代表你可以 · · ·
In the future...
长大后
you won't really become someone amazing.
你没变得多了不起
You still make mistakes.
还是会犯错
You still get confused.
还是会迷惘
You still regret for not having more ice,
会后悔没多吃一点冰淇淋
or not experiencing more relationships.
多谈几次恋爱
That's what I don't like about you.
我已经说过好几次我就是讨厌你这样
Same here.
我也讨厌你这样
Let's break up.
我们分手吧
And being too kind to people you dislike.
后悔没对讨厌的人更坏一点
And cherishing people you like more.
对喜欢的人更珍惜
But...
但是
the way you are is good.
这样的你也很好
You're still very brave,
还是很敢
very naive.
还是很天真
You still...
还是
scream for your idol.
会为了偶像尖叫
Ah!
啊
How can you stay so popular for 30 years?
为什么你红了三十年还没有过气
How come I still can't get a single ticket!
为什么三十年后我还是买不到你的票
Come on. Come on.
快快快
Truly glow stick!
真心萤光棒
See, I finally got the ticket.
你看我终于买到票了
Where?
哪里
I've queued for a long time!
排超久的你知道吗
I'm in the first row at the mosh pit.
我的是摇滚区那一排
Come on. Come on. Have a look.
快看 快看 参考一下啦 · · ·
Truly glow stick!
真心萤光棒
Come have a look.
参考一下
Hello.
欢迎光临小姐您好
May I help you?
想要喝什么呢
Kumquat lemonade, please.
我要一个金桔柠檬
No problem.
好的没有问题
30 dollars.
三十块
Hello.
你好欢迎光临
Bubble milk tea.
珍奶
Bubble milk tea? Sure.
珍奶吗 好 没问题
It's gonna take some time.
饮料现做稍等哦
You dropped something.
你东西掉了
I'm taking a break.
我出来透透气
Just treat me as an ordinary person.
你把我当作普通人就好了
Don't worry.
你放心
I think you're so ordinary.
我觉得你超普通的
I don't like you at all.
我一点都不喜欢你
I'm not your fan.
我更不是你的粉丝
This is... what my colleague...
这 · · ·个是我刚刚
helped me...
中午的时候
download earlier today.
我同事帮我下载的
So good.
唱得好好哦
I...don't know who's the singer...
也 · · ·不知道是谁唱的
I agree.
我也觉得
It's good.
蛮好听的
Let me play another song.
我把它关掉换一个
Can I take a photo with you?
我 · · ·可不可以跟你拍个照
Although you think I'm ordinary,
虽然你觉得我很普通
and you're not my fan.
不是我的粉丝
Can we... take a photo?
我能 拍吗
Yes...
可以 · · ·
Ok.
好
Sorry, I'm a bit...
对不起 我有点
nervous.
紧张
Good?
可以罗
Thanks.
谢谢
Ok.
好啦
By the way...
欵 · · ·
Can you sign for me?
可不可以麻烦帮我签个名啊
Sure.
好啊 来
Thanks.
谢谢
Oh!
哦
Can you please write...
可不可以麻烦再帮我写
To Lin Truly.
"To 林真心"
L.l.N.
双木林
Truly as in "Truly Madly Deeply".
真心诚意的"真心"
Lin Truly.
"林真心"
You're going to the concert tonight,
那今天晚上你去看演唱会吧
right?
是吧
How do you know?
你怎么知道
Because
没有
my concert is called "Truly Love You".
我的演唱会叫"真心爱你"
So...
所以
you really have to go.
你怎么样也要去
But I couldn't get any ticket.
可是我买不到票
All your concerts
你演唱会的票
are sold out.
卖光了都爆满
Call this person.
你打这个电话
He's our staff.
我工作人员
You have to come.
那一定要来哦
OK.
好
Thank you.
谢谢
Bye bye.
再见
Don't forget.
记得哦
Bye bye.
Bye Bye
Hello?
喂
Hi...
嗯那个你好
hmmm...
是
Andy Lau gave me this number.
Andy刘德华给我这个电话
I guess he told you about it, right?
他应该有交代你们吧
My name is.
我的名字叫做
Lin Truly.
林真心
Is sesame dressing...
麻酱面
still separated from noodles?
麻酱跟面还是分开放吗
The concert will start soon.
演唱会很快就开始了
Are you excited?
你们期待吗
I am.
我很期待
Because one of my friends made his efforts
因为我有一个朋友
to make the concert happen.
他很努力的去促成这一次的演唱会
He wanted to fulfill a promise he made
他想完成自己一个年轻的承诺
to his first love.
为了他的初恋情人
I like their story very much.
我很喜欢他们的故事
I want to dedicate this concert
这一次的演唱会
to everyone who has truly loved someone.
也希望送给所有真心爱过的朋友
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Truly love you.
真心爱你
Is that you...
这名字
come up with this title?
是你取的哦
Otherwise?
不然咧
The concert is starting soon.
演唱会快要开始罗
But...
可是
I didn't get any ticket.
我没有买到票
I'll ask...
我叫
Andy Lau
刘德华
to sing for you.
唱给你听
Yeah right.
最好是啦
Sure.
好啊
It's been a long time.
好久不见
《失恋阵线联盟》草蜢
她总是只留下电话号码
从不肯让我送他回家
听说你也曾经爱上过她
曾经也同样无法自拔
你说你学不会假装潇洒
却教我别太早放弃她
把过去全说成一段神话
然后笑彼此一样地傻
我们这么在乎她
却被他全部抹煞
越疼她越伤心
永远得不到回答
到底她怎么想
应该继续猜测吗
还是说好全忘了吧
找一个承认失恋的方法
让心情好好地放个假
当你我不小心又想起她
就在记忆里划一个 X
她总是只留下电话号码
从不肯让我送他回家
听说你也曾经爱上过她
曾经也同样无法自拔
你说你学不会假装潇洒
却教我别太早放弃她
把过去全说成一段神话
然后笑彼此一样地傻
我们这么在乎她
却被他全部抹煞
越疼她越伤心
永远得不到回答
到底她怎么想
应该继续猜测吗
还是说好全忘了吧
找一个承认失恋的方法
让心情好好地放个假
当你我不小心又想起她
就在记忆里划一个 x